# MARTIN MELGAR

# Data Analyst

#### Contact

## Nashville, TN (786) 366-7878 Martinmelg04@gmail.com

# Education

Bachelor of Arts Linguistics University of Florida, Gainesville

Data Analytics Certification Nashville Software School Expected Completion: August 19<sup>th</sup> ,2022

## **Key Skills**

Python
PowerBI
Tableau
PostgreSQL
Webscraping
Jupyter Frameworks
Microsoft Office - Excel
Bilingual - English and Spanish

## **Key Projects**

Ryman Events Webscraping
Nashville Cemetery Excel
Portfolio
UN GDP & Internet Python
Analysis
Lahmann Database SQL
Query

#### **About**

Analyst with a history in nonprofit data analysis and project management. Experience with common analysis frameworks SQL, Python, and Excel and keen critical thinking skills to overcome complex projects. Obtaining Data Analytics Certification in order to solve efficiency and key performance indicator queries.

### **Experience**

#### May 2022 - August 2022

#### **Data Analytics Apprentice • Nashville Software School**

- Develop data cleaning skills using Python, PostGreSQL, and Excel.
- Develop Data Visualization skills using PowerBi and Tableau.
- Work with real world data by assisting nonprofits and local government with data modeling and management.

#### February 2021 - May 2022

#### Member Services Agent • Device Team • Motus, LLC

- -Resolve a variety of issues via phone, email, and webchat.
- -Update Customer cases to Zendesk Management Platform.
- -Maintain average of 100+ tickets per day with 98% satisfaction rating.
- -Scheduled conference calls with both national and international accounts.

#### May 2020 — January 2021

#### **District Leader • Progressive Turnout**

- -Migrated mid-sized team on field-based operations.
- -Developed a business plan to distribute over 10,000 voter request notices.

#### November 2018 — March 2020

#### Technical Sales associate • Garmin Int'l

- -Expert in each segment of Garmin products.
- -Complete knowledge of software and hardware issues.
- -Collaborated with marketing team to stay relevant in ever changing environment.
- -Improve operations by increasing sales 17% year over year.

## June 2018 — September 2018

## Field Organizer • Engage Miami

- -Construct Events in the greater Miami area to increase voter awareness.
- -Worked closely with Miami-Dade College to promote engagement programs within the student body.
- -High school outreach program which consisted of events in Miami-Dade public schools to educate students on local Miami politics.